<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kepler/K2 Guest Observer Office Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>K2 Microlensing Campaign Workshop, May 7-8, 2015, NASA Ames Research Center, CA</title><link href="/k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-nasa-ames-research-center-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-nasa-ames-research-center-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In April of 2016, the NASA K2 mission will execute Campaign 9, a continuous 75-day long campaign targeting the galactic bulge dedicated to a single Microlensing Science Experiment. The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2"&gt;NASA K2 mission&lt;/a&gt; is sponsoring a &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop"&gt;1.5-day workshop on the topic of the K2 Microlensing Experiment&lt;/a&gt; on May 7-8, 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivations for holding this workshop are two-fold: Firstly to provide an opportunity for interactive planning for the K2 Microlensing Experiment amongst NASA, the K2 project and the scientific community; and secondly to serve as a pre-proposal discussion opportunity in advance of the submission of K2 Microlensing Science Team proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K2 project staff will describe the observing plan and operating procedures for up-linking target lists, down-linking the observed data and the time-line for archiving products. NASA HQ and K2 staff will present information regarding the proposal process, possible avenues for investigation, and funding. We are also inviting attendees to present information valuable in the planning and preparation for the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will begin at 9.00am PST on Thursday May 7 and end at 12.00pm PST on Friday May 8, 2015. The venue will be building &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Venue"&gt;N-232 at NASA Ames Research Center&lt;/a&gt;, in Mountain View, California. We are intending to have available limited facilities for &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Callin"&gt;virtual participation&lt;/a&gt;. To &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Apply"&gt;apply to attend the workshop&lt;/a&gt; either in-person or virtually you will need to fill in the &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/forms/ESGRMC8vOJ"&gt;application form&lt;/a&gt;. The deadline for applying to attend is April 17, 2015 at 4.00pm PST. A NASA visitor badge is required to attend in-person and will be provided only to registered participants. Workshop information is available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Campaign 2 Data Release</title><link href="/k2-campaign-2-data-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T02:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:k2-campaign-2-data-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Target Pixel Files from K2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;Campaign 2&lt;/a&gt; have been delivered and are &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/k2/"&gt;available at the MAST&lt;/a&gt;. Campaign 2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;target list&lt;/a&gt; consists of 13,399 standard long cadence and 54 short cadence targets. In addition we have included large pixel masks over the clusters M4 and M80. If a target falls within either the M4 or M80 large mask it will not appear in the target list. Two Solar System bodies were selected - trans-Neptunian object (278361) 2007 JJ43 and Comet C/2013 A1 (Siding Spring). The Solar System bodies are moving relative to the celestial sphere and are covered by long streaks of pixels. The full cluster and Solar System pixel masks are made up of many smaller masks. Data release notes are available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Kepler Robovetted KOI table released</title><link href="/kepler-robovetted-koi-table-released.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:kepler-robovetted-koi-table-released.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Kepler project has opened the Q1-Q17 DR24 KOI table at the &lt;a href="http://exoplanetarchive.ipac.caltech.edu"&gt;NASA Exoplanet Archive&lt;/a&gt;, adding 1368 new Kepler Objects of Interest (KOIs) to the cumulative table. This is a milestone release because it utilizes the first uniform processing of the entire Kepler data set and it represents a first attempt at fully automating the dispositioning process so as to produce a uniformly vetted catalog of planetary candidates (PCs) and false positives (FPs). This is being done via the use of "robovetters" - sophisticated decision trees that utilize a set of targeted metrics to mimic the decision-making process. While all KOIs in the Q1-Q17 DR24 KOI table are given dispositions, work on the robovetters is not yet complete. Thus, before the table is closed more KOIs will be added and dispositions will change. To get more information about this KOI table and to download the data it contains go to NExScI.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Extracted K2 Lightcurves From Vanderburg and Johnson Now Available at MAST</title><link href="/extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new MAST High Level Science Product from K2 has been delivered that includes extracted lightcurves. Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1408.3853"&gt;Vanderburg and Johnson (2014)&lt;/a&gt;, long-cadence targets from Campaigns 0 and 1 now have detrended, extracted lightcurves available at MAST, including 20 different photometric apertures. There's a MAST Classic Search Interface so you can get lightcurves based on target IDs, coordinates, EPIC catalog fluxes, etc. You can also use our interactive plotter to explore the lightcurves using any of the photometric apertures before downloading the FITS files. Check out all the details here: &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/"&gt;http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>