<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kepler and K2</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/</id><updated>2015-05-04T01:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Geert Barentsen and Knicole Colón join the Guest Observer Office</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/geert-barentsen-and-knicole-colon-join-the-guest-observer-office.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-04T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-05-04:blog/geert-barentsen-and-knicole-colon-join-the-guest-observer-office.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Kepler/K2 Guest Observer Office has two new members joining us at Ames Research Center in California: Geert Barentsen and Knicole Colón.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Geert Barentsen joins us from the University of Hertfordshire in the UK. Geert's background is in the exploitation of data from wide-area Galactic Plane Surveys. In Hertfordshire leads the data processing and analysis of two projects which aim to map our own Galaxy in unprecedented detail: &lt;a href="http://www.iphas.org/"&gt;IPHAS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.vphas.eu"&gt;VPHAS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geert earned his doctorate at the Queen's University of Belfast in 2012 where he studied star formation in the Northern Galactic Plane. Prior to his PhD, he obtained a Master's degree in Computer Science at the University of Antwerp in Belgium, after which he gained professional experience as a data scientist at the European Space Agency in The Netherlands and the Royal Meteorological Institute in Belgium. In his spare time, he studies the activity of meteor showers using data collected by amateur astronomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Knicole Colón leaves a postdoctoral role at Lehigh University at a member of the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kilodegree_Extremely_Little_Telescope"&gt;KELT project&lt;/a&gt; to join us at Kepler. Her research interest are in the discovery and characterization of transiting exoplanets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a graduate student at the University of Florida, Knicole demonstrated the capability of OSIRIS on the 10.4-m Gran Telescopio Canarias (GTC) for exoplanet science. He postdoctoral experience at the University of Hawaii and Lehigh have focused on the characterization exoplanet atmospheres and in the confirmation of planets discovered by the KELT transit survey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geert will start his new role in June 2015 and Knicole will join us a month later in July.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Microlensing Campaign Draft Agenda Now Available</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/k2-microlensing-campaign-draft-agenda-now-available.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-24T06:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-04-24:blog/k2-microlensing-campaign-draft-agenda-now-available.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Agenda/"&gt;draft agenda&lt;/a&gt; is now available for the &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/"&gt;K2 Microlensing Workshop&lt;/a&gt;. This will likely be updated as we get closer to the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Venue/"&gt;venue for the workshop&lt;/a&gt; will be the SETI Institute in Mountain View, CA. Note that this is a change to the originally advertised venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be talks from Steve Howell (K2 Project Scientist, NASA Ames), Tom Barclay (K2 Guest Observer Office Director, NASA Ames), Doug Hudgins (NASA Exoplanet Exploration Program Scientist and K2 Deputy Program Scientist, NASA HQ) and Fergal Mullally (K2 Science Officer, NASA Ames), in addition to contributed talks from members of the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Microlensing Campaign Workshop, May 7-8, 2015, SETI Inst., CA</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-seti-inst-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-24T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-04-24:blog/k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-seti-inst-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that this meeting will now be hosted at the SETI Inst.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April of 2016, the NASA K2 mission will execute Campaign 9, a continuous 75-day long campaign targeting the galactic bulge dedicated to a single Microlensing Science Experiment. The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2"&gt;NASA K2 mission&lt;/a&gt; is sponsoring a &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop"&gt;1.5-day workshop on the topic of the K2 Microlensing Experiment&lt;/a&gt; on May 7-8, 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivations for holding this workshop are two-fold: Firstly to provide an opportunity for interactive planning for the K2 Microlensing Experiment amongst NASA, the K2 project and the scientific community; and secondly to serve as a pre-proposal discussion opportunity in advance of the submission of K2 Microlensing Science Team proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K2 project staff will describe the observing plan and operating procedures for up-linking target lists, down-linking the observed data and the time-line for archiving products. NASA HQ and K2 staff will present information regarding the proposal process, possible avenues for investigation, and funding. We are also inviting attendees to present information valuable in the planning and preparation for the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will begin at 9.00am PST on Thursday May 7 and end at 12.00pm PST on Friday May 8, 2015. The venue will be the SETI Institute in Mountain View, California. We are intending to have available limited facilities for &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Callin"&gt;virtual participation&lt;/a&gt;. To &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Apply"&gt;apply to attend the workshop&lt;/a&gt; either in-person or virtually you will need to fill in the &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/forms/ESGRMC8vOJ"&gt;application form&lt;/a&gt;. The deadline for applying to attend is April 17, 2015 at 4.00pm PST. Workshop information is available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Campaign 2 Data Release</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/k2-campaign-2-data-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T02:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-04-02:blog/k2-campaign-2-data-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Target Pixel Files from K2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;Campaign 2&lt;/a&gt; have been delivered and are &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/k2/"&gt;available at the MAST&lt;/a&gt;. Campaign 2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;target list&lt;/a&gt; consists of 13,399 standard long cadence and 54 short cadence targets. In addition we have included large pixel masks over the clusters M4 and M80. If a target falls within either the M4 or M80 large mask it will not appear in the target list. Two Solar System bodies were selected - trans-Neptunian object (278361) 2007 JJ43 and Comet C/2013 A1 (Siding Spring). The Solar System bodies are moving relative to the celestial sphere and are covered by long streaks of pixels. The full cluster and Solar System pixel masks are made up of many smaller masks. Data release notes are available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Kepler Robovetted KOI table released</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/kepler-robovetted-koi-table-released.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T01:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-04-02:blog/kepler-robovetted-koi-table-released.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Kepler project has opened the Q1-Q17 DR24 KOI table at the &lt;a href="http://exoplanetarchive.ipac.caltech.edu"&gt;NASA Exoplanet Archive&lt;/a&gt;, adding 1368 new Kepler Objects of Interest (KOIs) to the cumulative table. This is a milestone release because it utilizes the first uniform processing of the entire Kepler data set and it represents a first attempt at fully automating the dispositioning process so as to produce a uniformly vetted catalog of planetary candidates (PCs) and false positives (FPs). This is being done via the use of "robovetters" - sophisticated decision trees that utilize a set of targeted metrics to mimic the decision-making process. While all KOIs in the Q1-Q17 DR24 KOI table are given dispositions, work on the robovetters is not yet complete. Thus, before the table is closed more KOIs will be added and dispositions will change. To get more information about this KOI table and to download the data it contains go to NExScI.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Extracted K2 Lightcurves From Vanderburg and Johnson Now Available at MAST</title><link href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/blog/extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov,2015-04-02:blog/extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new MAST High Level Science Product from K2 has been delivered that includes extracted lightcurves. Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1408.3853"&gt;Vanderburg and Johnson (2014)&lt;/a&gt;, long-cadence targets from Campaigns 0 and 1 now have detrended, extracted lightcurves available at MAST, including 20 different photometric apertures. There's a MAST Classic Search Interface so you can get lightcurves based on target IDs, coordinates, EPIC catalog fluxes, etc. You can also use our interactive plotter to explore the lightcurves using any of the photometric apertures before downloading the FITS files. Check out all the details here: &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/"&gt;http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>