<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Kepler &amp; K2</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/k2.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-08-17T14:00:00-07:00</updated><entry><title>Call for Spectroscopy Targets for UKIRT Program</title><link href="/call-for-spectroscopy-targets-for-ukirt-program.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-08-17T14:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Knicole Colon</name></author><id>tag:,2015-08-17:call-for-spectroscopy-targets-for-ukirt-program.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Kepler/K2 project office has been awarded 30 hours to use &lt;a href="http://www.ukirt.hawaii.edu/instruments/uist/uist.html"&gt;UIST&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://www.ukirt.hawaii.edu/"&gt;UKIRT&lt;/a&gt; for spectroscopic characterization of K2 targets.  The aim of the UKIRT program is to provide a uniform catalog of K-band spectra of K2 targets of interest, with a focus on cool exoplanet hosts discovered by K2.  We expect to acquire spectra of ~90 K2 targets in the 2015B semester.  Targets from Campaigns 0, 3, and 4 are visible around December/January, August/September, and November, respectively.  Members of the community are encouraged to submit targets for this program to the &lt;a href="mailto:keplergo@mail.arc.nasa.gov"&gt;GO Office&lt;/a&gt;, keeping in mind that all spectra will be made publicly available on the &lt;a href="https://cfop.ipac.caltech.edu/k2/"&gt;ExoFOP&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Campaign 3 data release</title><link href="/k2-campaign-3-data-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-21T10:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Geert Barentsen</name></author><id>tag:,2015-07-21:k2-campaign-3-data-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Campaign 3 target pixel files, light curves, and full frame images are now
available for download from the
&lt;a href="https://archive.stsci.edu/k2/"&gt;K2 data archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC03.shtml"&gt;C3 target list&lt;/a&gt;
included 16,375 standard long cadence and 55 standard short cadence targets.
In addition, custom pixel apertures were collected along the trajectories of
dwarf planet (225088) 2007 OR10, the planet Neptune, and its moon Nereid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data release notes are available at
&lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C3drn.shtml"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C3drn.shtml&lt;/a&gt;.
We strongly encourage users to read the release notes.
In particular, we draw attention to the following changes
in the data processing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The background level is now removed from the calibrated pixel flux provided
by the target pixel files (column FLUX), bringing the K2 TPF files in line
with those that were previously made available for the prime Kepler mission.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New quality flags now indicate which cadences were obtained during a thruster firing (column QUALITY).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple Aperture Photometry (SAP_FLUX) and cotrended (PDCSAP_FLUX) light curves are now available for long cadence data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Got a hook? The Kepler/K2 press team would like to hear from you.</title><link href="/got-a-hook-the-keplerk2-press-team-would-like-to-hear-from-you.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-14T02:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Tom Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-07-14:got-a-hook-the-keplerk2-press-team-would-like-to-hear-from-you.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The K2 mission, the repurposing of the prolific planet-hunting Kepler spacecraft, is an achievement that spans well beyond the NASA team and across the science and engineering communities. The resulting new scientific observation opportunities are a testament to ingenuity and teamwork, and we would like to help bring attention to your great work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While all results are scientifically significant, there are some that hold the added luster of public appeal. At the basic level, public appeal can be qualified as 'firsts' (the first Earth-sized planet); has a tie to popular culture (Kepler-16b or "Tatooine" and is also a 'first'); or sparks curiosity (catching a supernova before the explosion, or a disintegrating planet). These are the hooks that grab the attention of the public and spurs additional learning. A news hook can be obvious but can require discussion to ferret out the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a science result that may have public appeal, and will soon be accepted for publication in a peer-reviewed journal, please contact &lt;a href="mailto:michele.johnson@nasa.gov"&gt;Michele Johnson&lt;/a&gt;. Of most immediate interest are those results that will be announced at the IAU General Assembly in August. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Anticipated Observing and Archiving Dates Now Listed Online</title><link href="/anticipated-observing-and-archiving-dates-now-listed-online.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Tom Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-07-13:anticipated-observing-and-archiving-dates-now-listed-online.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;To assist folks with planning their K2 related activities (follow-up observing, graduate student work, etc.) &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/Fields.shtml"&gt;we have made available the anticipated dates&lt;/a&gt; that we will archive pixel level and light curve data at &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/k2/"&gt;the MAST&lt;/a&gt; for all K2 campaigns through to C13. These dates are subject to change due of programmatic activities and may come in or slip out. We will keep these dates updated as we are able.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Campaign 3 data processing complete</title><link href="/campaign-3-data-processing-complete.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-07-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Geert Barentsen</name></author><id>tag:,2015-07-09:campaign-3-data-processing-complete.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data processing for K2 Campaign 3 is now complete
and the pixel files are in the process of being transferred to the &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/k2"&gt;MAST archive&lt;/a&gt;.
We anticipate that the data will become available to the public by July 15, 2015. This data release will include both pixel level data and project created light curves.
As for previous campaigns, there will be no proprietary period for using or publishing K2 data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC03.shtml"&gt;Campaign 3 target list&lt;/a&gt; included 16,375 standard long cadence and 55 standard short cadence targets.
In addition we have included large pixel masks over dwarf planet (225088) 2007 OR10, the planet Neptune and its moon Nereid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on this blog for a release announcement and associated data release notes.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Campaign 6 Target list available online</title><link href="/campaign-6-target-list-available-online.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-26T09:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-06-26:campaign-6-target-list-available-online.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The K2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC06.shtml"&gt;Campaign 6 Target List&lt;/a&gt; has now been posted. This target list consists of 28,289 standard long cadence and 84 standard short cadence targets. In addition we have included large pixel masks over 65 Trojan Asteroids. Bodies within our own Solar System move relative to the celestial sphere and are covered by long streaks of pixels. We tiled the just a subset of the pixels that make up the path the Trojans move along. These observations are in long cadence. These observations are due to start in early-July.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Save the date for the K2 Science Conference. November 2-5, 2015</title><link href="/save-the-date-for-the-k2-science-conference-november-2-5-2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-03T06:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-06-03:save-the-date-for-the-k2-science-conference-november-2-5-2015.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The LCOGT (Las Cumbres Observatory Global Telescope Network) invites the whole astronomical community to celebrate the science from the first year of the NASA K2 mission in Santa Barbara, California. The meeting will take place November 2-5, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organizers encourage K2 users to present early scientific results from all areas of research, from our own Solar System and exoplanets to young stars and distant galaxies.  Attendees will hear updates on the mission and discuss the latest in data processing techniques.  The organizers also encourage contributions on results from the Kepler prime mission and the future TESS mission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a href="http://lcogt.net/k2scicon/"&gt;conference website&lt;/a&gt; in the coming weeks for updates and registration. Questions may be addressed to the &lt;a href="mailto:k2scicon-loc@lcogt.net"&gt;LOC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Campaign 5 Target list available online</title><link href="/campaign-5-target-list-available-online.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-02T09:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-06-02:campaign-5-target-list-available-online.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The K2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC05.shtml"&gt;Campaign 5 Target List&lt;/a&gt; has now been posted. The Campaign 5 target list consists of 25,099 standard long cadence and 204 standard short cadence targets. In addition we have included large pixel masks over dwarf planet (126154) 2002 YH140. We also observed the open cluster M67. The cluster was tiled with 73 individual apertures to create a contiguous 400x400 pixel region over two channels.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Additional Targets Available in Future K2 Campaigns</title><link href="/additional-targets-available-in-future-k2-campaigns.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-06-02T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-06-02:additional-targets-available-in-future-k2-campaigns.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As some of you prepare your K2 Cycle 3 proposal target lists I wanted to alert you to an increase in the number of targets that we can observe with K2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our pointing has been significantly better than our conservative pointing assumptions we used when we built our pixel cost algorithms. The result of this is that we can observe about double the number of targets from Campaign 5 onwards compared with Campaign 4 and earlier. The increase is from about 15,000 total to around 30,000 total. Unfortunately, the telemetry data to determine that we were able to do this was no available in time for the K2 GO Cycle 2 proposal deadline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does this affect you? You may wish to consider submitting larger target lists than in previous cycles in any Cycle 3 proposals you are submitting. Now, as always there is a caveat here that you should not propose more target than you can justify but please be aware that the cost of a target is now lower.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Due date for K2 Guest Observer Cycle 3 Step-1 Proposal Fast Approaching</title><link href="/due-date-for-k2-guest-observer-cycle-3-step-1-proposal-fast-approaching.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-29T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-29:due-date-for-k2-guest-observer-cycle-3-step-1-proposal-fast-approaching.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The K2 Guest Observer Cycle 3 proposal call is observations of targets in Campaigns 8 and 10. The due date for Step-1 proposals (essentially a compulsory notice of intent) is June 2, 2015 at midnight Eastern Time. Investigators may not submit a Full Proposal (Step-2) without first submitting a Step-1 proposal by the due date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycle 3 also include Campaign 9, which is dedicated to observing gravitational microlensing events. No proposals seeking to observe targets in C9 will be considered. The proposal call for this campaign is to join a Microlensing Science Team.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>ExoFOP-K2 website launched</title><link href="/exofop-k2-website-launched.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-05T12:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-05-05:exofop-k2-website-launched.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cfop.ipac.caltech.edu/k2/"&gt;ExoFOP-K2&lt;/a&gt; is a web site designed to optimize resources and facilitate collaboration in follow-up studies of K2 targets. It serves as a repository for community-gathered follow-up data and is supported by the NASA &lt;a href="http://exoplanetarchive.ipac.caltech.edu/index.html"&gt;Exoplanet Archive&lt;/a&gt; infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to continuing to support Kepler via the original &lt;a href="https://cfop.ipac.caltech.edu/home/"&gt;CFOP website&lt;/a&gt;, this new service includes the K2 targets, and will eventually be expanded to support future missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is open to the entire community and currently contains magnitudes, finding charts, and nearby source lists for the targets from Campaigns 0-4 and the engineering campaign. A new feature allows users to designate possible planetary candidates, false positives and eclipsing binaries. ExoFOP-K2 will allow detailed searches of K2 targets similar to the CFOP search pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All content can be viewed and downloaded without logging in. A username and password are only required if you wish to upload data, notes, or files. Existing CFOP user name and password will work on ExoFOP-K2.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Microlensing Campaign Draft Agenda Now Available</title><link href="/k2-microlensing-campaign-draft-agenda-now-available.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-24T06:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-24:k2-microlensing-campaign-draft-agenda-now-available.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Agenda/"&gt;draft agenda&lt;/a&gt; is now available for the &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/"&gt;K2 Microlensing Workshop&lt;/a&gt;. This will likely be updated as we get closer to the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Venue/"&gt;venue for the workshop&lt;/a&gt; will be the SETI Institute in Mountain View, CA. Note that this is a change to the originally advertised venue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be talks from Steve Howell (K2 Project Scientist, NASA Ames), Tom Barclay (K2 Guest Observer Office Director, NASA Ames), Doug Hudgins (NASA Exoplanet Exploration Program Scientist and K2 Deputy Program Scientist, NASA HQ) and Fergal Mullally (K2 Science Officer, NASA Ames), in addition to contributed talks from members of the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Microlensing Campaign Workshop, May 7-8, 2015, SETI Inst., CA</title><link href="/k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-seti-inst-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-24T05:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-24:k2-microlensing-campaign-workshop-may-7-8-2015-seti-inst-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In April of 2016, the NASA K2 mission will execute Campaign 9, a continuous 75-day long campaign targeting the galactic bulge dedicated to a single Microlensing Science Experiment. The &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2"&gt;NASA K2 mission&lt;/a&gt; is sponsoring a &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop"&gt;1.5-day workshop on the topic of the K2 Microlensing Experiment&lt;/a&gt; on May 7-8, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The motivations for holding this workshop are two-fold: Firstly to provide an opportunity for interactive planning for the K2 Microlensing Experiment amongst NASA, the K2 project and the scientific community; and secondly to serve as a pre-proposal discussion opportunity in advance of the submission of K2 Microlensing Science Team proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;K2 project staff will describe the observing plan and operating procedures for up-linking target lists, down-linking the observed data and the time-line for archiving products. NASA HQ and K2 staff will present information regarding the proposal process, possible avenues for investigation, and funding. We are also inviting attendees to present information valuable in the planning and preparation for the experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will begin at 9.00am PST on Thursday May 7 and end at 12.00pm PST on Friday May 8, 2015. The venue will be the SETI Institute in Mountain View, California. We are intending to have available limited facilities for virtual participation. To &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/Apply"&gt;apply to attend the workshop&lt;/a&gt; either in-person or virtually you will need to fill in the &lt;a href="http://goo.gl/forms/ESGRMC8vOJ"&gt;application form&lt;/a&gt;. The deadline for applying to attend is April 17, 2015 at 4.00pm PST. Workshop information is available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2MicrolensingWorkshop/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>K2 Campaign 2 Data Release</title><link href="/k2-campaign-2-data-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T02:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:k2-campaign-2-data-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Target Pixel Files from K2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;Campaign 2&lt;/a&gt; have been delivered and are &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/k2/"&gt;available at the MAST&lt;/a&gt;. Campaign 2 &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/GuestInvestigationsC02.shtml"&gt;target list&lt;/a&gt; consists of 13,399 standard long cadence and 54 short cadence targets. In addition we have included large pixel masks over the clusters M4 and M80. If a target falls within either the M4 or M80 large mask it will not appear in the target list. Two Solar System bodies were selected - trans-Neptunian object (278361) 2007 JJ43 and Comet C/2013 A1 (Siding Spring). The Solar System bodies are moving relative to the celestial sphere and are covered by long streaks of pixels. The full cluster and Solar System pixel masks are made up of many smaller masks. Data release notes are available at &lt;a href="http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml"&gt;http://keplerscience.arc.nasa.gov/K2/C2drn.shtml&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Extracted K2 Lightcurves From Vanderburg and Johnson Now Available at MAST</title><link href="/extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Thomas Barclay</name></author><id>tag:,2015-04-02:extracted-k2-lightcurves-from-vanderburg-and-johnson-now-available-at-mast.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A new MAST High Level Science Product from K2 has been delivered that includes extracted lightcurves. Courtesy of &lt;a href="http://arxiv.org/abs/1408.3853"&gt;Vanderburg and Johnson (2014)&lt;/a&gt;, long-cadence targets from Campaigns 0 and 1 now have detrended, extracted lightcurves available at MAST, including 20 different photometric apertures. There's a MAST Classic Search Interface so you can get lightcurves based on target IDs, coordinates, EPIC catalog fluxes, etc. You can also use our interactive plotter to explore the lightcurves using any of the photometric apertures before downloading the FITS files. Check out all the details here: &lt;a href="http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/"&gt;http://archive.stsci.edu/prepds/k2sff/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>